Now, at first glass, reducing the payload of each transfer, and
only transmitting data when it's required seems like a sound approach.
You're reducing the amount of data being transferred, so that's less
data on the network. That's less superfluous work being done storing processing
data on the device. It's basically a case of putting off
any work, until you actually know you need to do it.
But it turns out that this approach has it's drawbacks, compared
to the big cookie model of all of that work up front.
So, overall, this is a better solution. But let's take a closer look at the big
cookie model. And to do that, we really
need to understand the underlying cell radio state machine.